Now, in this section, we are going to use our data structure in real life project, so I'll show you
how to implement our data structure in real life project and how it helps us to make the things possible
that were not possible without error.
So in this project, we are going to take the daily temperature from the user as an input and then we
are going to calculate the average of these temperature and then we will find out how many days is above
the average temperature.
Now our project will look like this.
So here, as I mentioned, we are going to find a number of days above the average temperature.
So to find the number of days above the average temperature, we need to find out the average temperature.
Then we need to check that reached these temperature is above the average temperature.
Now, when we run, our program is going to look like this.
First, it will ask how many days temperature we are going to input, because initial step is we need
to identify how many days temperature we are going to measure.
So, for example, for simplicity, if I put two over here and hit Enter is going to prompt me another
input question.
So it's going to ask the first high temperature.
So for our kids, I'm going to put one for first these temperature.
So as you see, we have said here, too.
So that's what is going to ask secondees temperature over here.
So how many days that we set over here, that number of days, temperatures will be asked from us over
here.
So for the second day, if I put, for example, two and then hit Enter is going to print out saying
that the average temperature is one point five and one, these temperature is above the average temperature.
So if you look at this example over here, you see that secondees temperature is above the average temperature
because average temperature is one point five.
So we are going to implement this project using our data structure.
Now, let's see how this is working in practice.
So by the end of this section, you will be able to make a program like this.
So in this case, if you run our program, you will see that the first thing that it does, it ask how
many days temperature in this case, if I put three over here, hit enter, you'll see that it is ask
the once high temperature, for example, if I put over here 10 and hit enter, it's going to ask the
high temperature for day two.
I'm going to put 20, then hit enter.
It will ask the three high temperature.
So for the three I'm going to put 15 and hit enter.
So after finding it you see that it returns.
US average temperature is 15 and one day's temperature is above average.
So in this case, secondees temperature is 24, which is above average.
So it's returning like this.
Now, by the end of this section, you will be able to make a project like this using our data structure.
So let's continue to implement our project.