So as I mentioned before, our project is consists of two parts.
So first, we need to find the average temperature, then we need to find out how many days is above
the average temperature.
Now, in this case, we can find the average temperature without using a radiator structure.
So let's see, how can we implement it without using a radiator structure?
Then we will find out how our data structure makes things possible that we're not impossible before.
So in this case, as I said before, the first thing that I am going to do, I need to get input from
a user.
So in Java, to get input from user, we can use this scanner.
So by using scanner class, we can get the values from the console and use it in our program.
So in this case, what I'm going to do, the first thing that I'm going to do, I'm going to create
an instance of this kind of class.
So to use, Carol, because you need to then inside this main method, I'm going to implement our project.
So the first thing that I'm going to do, I'm going to initialize scanner class console.
So I will name it.
Console is equal to a new scanner.
So inside this one is going to be system.
So it is line of code.
We are initializing our scanner class.
So then after realizing this, I need to print out message to ask from the user how many days temperature
we are going to use.
So in this case, I need to talk message to the council so we know that in Java to print out message
to the council, we are using print method.
So I'm going to call system, not out of print.
So inside print statement, I'm going to ask how many days temperature.
Then after doing so, I'm going to get the number of days.
So a story in an integer variable.
So I'm going to create integer variable numbers so it will get input from the console.
So to get input from the console, I'm going to put console.
So this is kind of a class over here console the next end.
So in this case, it's going to be integer number.
So that's why I'm putting it over here.
So after getting them, I need to calculate the some of them and then using a number of days, we are
going to calculate the average of these days.
So we know that to calculate average, we need to take some of all these temperature and divide it by
number of days.
So in this case, I'm going to create another variable for some and initially it will be set to zero.
Then I'm going to loop through one until the number of days and get these temperature from the console.
So to do so, I'm going to write love like this.
So for print I equal one.
So it will continue.
I was an equal to this, so we need to get all the temperature.
Then it will be increased by one.
So inside this loop, I'm going to print out to the console asking the day's temperatures.
So I'll just copy this code from here and put it inside this room so I will change the message inside
this one.
So as you remember, the first thing was they saw here, which is temperature is going to be a high
class item.
Then one more time they are going to cocounsel next it to get the integer variable from the console
and added to the somebody below here.
So next variable will be comes out next.
And then we are going to add it to some some class will be next.
So it is called over here.
We are getting the day's temperature from the console and adding them to the sun variable or here.
So it depends on the number of days we have inserted over here.
So if you have a certain number of days, for example, two is going to ask two days temperature over
here.
So we are going to add it to the sun variable over here.
Now, after adding it, we need to calculate the average temperature.
So average temperature will be double data types.
So I'm going to create the average variable and calculate the average temperature.
So to calculate average temperature, we are going to take some divided by number of days.
Then after calculating this, we are going to print out to the council average temperature.
So it's going to be like this.
So here you need it to be double.
So here I am going to print out to the council.
I just need to put one space to the council.
So that's why I put Winterland first.
Then I'm going to print out to the council this one.
So print one.
It's going to be averaged ten plus average.
Now it is we have concluded a calculation of average temperature.
So if you run our code, you will see that the first thing that it does, it ask a number of days temperature.
So this line of code is executed over here and it comes over here to wait for the next line of code.
So we need to input number of days, for example, for simplicity.
If I put two over here and hit enter.
So you see that it continues to the inside of this loop over here in which it's asking, did they want
high temperature?
So if I put over here 10.
Hit enter, it's looping again, this loop over here and asking for the next day's temperatures for
next day's temperature.
I'm going to put 20 and hit enter is going to print out to the console.
Average temperature is 15.
Now, everything works over here smoothly and we have not used our data structure.
But the question over here is, how do you count how many days were above the average?
So we could try to incorporate it inside this loop over here, but it won't work.
The problem is you cannot figure out the average until you have gone through all of the data.
This means that you need to make a second pass through the data to figure out how many days were average
temperatures.
So after getting all these temperature, we are calculating the average temperature.
Then one more time we need to loop through these days of temperature and find out which these temperature
is above the average temperature now inside this loop.
We cannot do it because we have to look through all these temperature.
Then we can calculate the average temperature.
So this means that we cannot do it using of class because a scanner class has no reset option that allows
you to see the data.
Second time you would have to prompt the user, enter temperature a second time so we can use kind of
class to prompt the user to enter the temperature a second time.
But this will be very silly because in professional programs we can only ask data from a user one time
and use it several times in our code.
So that's why we cannot ask using kind of a second time, because by mistake they can enter a different
data.
And actually no one wants to enter same information twice to the program.
So how can we solve this problem?
Fortunately, we can solve this problem with the array as the user enters the number.
We can compute to come to some and we can save this data in our area.
So then after saving that, we can make second pass through the array in which we have saved all this
temperature and find out the average temperature.
Now, in the next lecture, we are going to implement this logic in our program.