Nine days later, we are going to implement a radiator structure in our program to calculate the number
of days that are above the average temperature.
So I'm going to change this code to use our data structure in this court.
So as we said before, without using our data structure, we cannot calculate the number of days above
the average temperature.
So that's why we are going to use our data structure.
So it is you will understand how a rate data structure is very useful in cases like this.
Now, as we said before, the first thing that we are going to do, we are getting the input from the
user.
So here we are going to use Kanakas.
So I'm not going to touch this part of code over here.
Then in the next line of code, we are printing out to the council and asking the number of days from
the user.
So this will remain same and this part also will remain same.
We are getting the number of days and save it to the days variable.
Now here after this one, I'm going to create a new array over here which will store each day's temperature.
So here the array type will be integer.
So I'm going to declare it like this and then there will be temps which would restore the temperatures.
Then it's going to be initialized like this.
Now, you might be interested how many cells will be in this area.
So it's going to be a number of days because we will have only this number of temperatures in our area.
That's why we have initialise early with this sizable number of days.
So after initializing this temporary over here, we are going to record the temperatures for each day
and save them in this area over here.
And then when we are seeing them parallel, we are going to find the average temperature.
So here I'm going to comment something like this, record temperature and find the average.
So by collecting this, you will know that this section is blown to recording the temperatures and finding
the average.
So here I am not going to touch this variable over here because we are saving the some of the temperatures
in this variable.
So inside the loop, we are going to ask from a user to enter the each day's temperature.
So while entering it this time, I'm not going to save it in this next variable over here.
I'm going to save them in the temps over here.
So here is going to be like this.
We are going to put like this then based on this, we are going to calculate the sum of temperature.
So each time a user enters the data, it saves in this temperature area over here.
Interesting moment over here that we know that array index starts from zero.
But here we put it starts from day one.
So this means that we need to change the loop to start from the zero and it continues until the number
of days.
So the number of days will not be included over here because we are starting from zero.
But if you do so and printing out to the council is going to ask from a user, they rose High-temperature
first.
So to prevent this misunderstanding, I'm going to put over here I plus one.
So in this case, it's going to be a plus one.
So it will be inside passes for that.
This is different from everything.
So from user, it will ask the wants temperature, but in the array it will store these days once temperature
at the index of zero.
Then you calculate the sum of these temperatures over here.
So with this, we are calculating the sum of temperatures.
Then inside this average variable, we are going to calculate the average temperature for everything
over here remains same.
So after finding the average temperature, we need to find out the number of days that are above the
average temperature.
So that's where I'm going to comment over here, can't they?
Above average.
Now, how can we do that?
Now, you've said that we are saving all temperatures in this area over here.
So if you are saving all temperatures in this area, we can look through this area and finding out the
number of days that are above the average because we have already calculate the average and we have
the all this temperature inside this temperature area.
So this means that by looking through this area, we can compare that if the temperature is above the
average or so for this first I'm going to create a variable above and initially it will set to zero
because we know it's zero number of days are greater than the average temperature.
So then we look through this area over here.
So I'm going to write a book like this and I will start from zero because starts from the index of zero
and it will continue onto the length of arrays for the length of a range of will be calculated by using.
And each time it will increase by one.
So inside this loop, I'm going to write if conditions like this, if temps I is greater than average,
then in this case I'm going to increase this above variable by one.
So it's going to increase by one and it will continue until we have checked all these temperatures over
here.
Then at the end, I'm going to print out the average temperature, then the number of days that are
greater than the average temperature.
So I'm going to copy.
Print statement and put it over here, and I'm going to change it like this.
They average every so here I am going to put a ball.
So with this, we have completed our project.
So basically what we are doing over here is we are taking the number of days from the user.
And based on this variable nowadays over here, they are asking the user if these temperatures so while
a user enters the temperature, they are saving them.
This array over here.
Then based on this one, we are calculating the sum of these temperatures.
And then based on this one, we are calculating the average temperature using number of days.
Then after calculating the average temperature one more time via looping through the array and finding
out how many days temperature is above the average temperature.
So as we said before, without using our data structure, we cannot calculate the number of days that
are above the average temperature because we need to save this data in any data structure.
So in this case, we are saving it in the array.
Now, if we run our code, you will see that first it asks number of days temperature.
So here I'm going to put three, then I'm going to insert five for the first day's high temperature
for the second day, high temperature.
I'm going to insert 20 for the 30 days.
High temperature, I'm going to insert twenty five.
So if I heat enter, you see that two days temperature is above the average and the average temperature
is 16.
So they twos and threes temperatures are above the average temperature.
So with this, we have come to the end of this letter.
So hopefully everything is clear about how can we implement our data structure in real life project.
So see you in the next lecture.